shell.us 2011-10-06

# Privacy Policy - United States

  * What does this privacy policy cover? 
  * Personally Identifiable Information That We Collect 
  * E-mail Newsletter Subscriptions 
  * User Accounts 
  * Promotions, Credit Cards and Purchases 
  * Customer Service 
  * Non-Personally Identifiable Information That We Collect 
  * Cookies and Related Technology 
  * Special Notice - if you are under 13 years old 
  * Non-Personally Identifiable Information 
  * Personally Identifiable Information 
  * Keeping our records accurate 
  * Security of your personal data 
  * Use of your personal information submitted to other web sites 
  * Data transfers 
  * Will this privacy policy change? 
  * How you can contact us 

###  What does this privacy policy cover? 

This privacy policy covers our use of your personal information that is collected through or in connection with the web site (this “site”) for Shell Oil Company in the United States (“Shell US”).

Other Shell web sites may contain privacy policies that are different from this privacy policy. On your journey around the Shell web sites please check the privacy policy of each web site that you visit.

Your use of any this site constitutes acceptance of this Privacy Policy and any other applicable terms. The Terms of Service for this site are hereby incorporated by reference.

###  Personally Identifiable Information That We Collect 

Shell US respects your privacy and is committed to protecting personally identifiable information that you provide in connection with your use of this site and services.

###  E-mail Newsletter Subscriptions 

To subscribe to our e-mail newsletters, you will need to provide your e-mail address. You may also be asked for other information when you subscribe.

###  User Accounts 

In order to use certain services you will need to register and create a user account ("User Account"). You may be asked to choose a user name, screen name, or member name (each, a "User Name") and password.

Please do not use your real name or the real name of another person when selecting a User Name. You will also be asked to provide certain personally identifiable information and other information about yourself, such as your first and last name, address, telephone number, and e-mail address.

Please note that your User Name will be available to the Internet's general public while you participate in some services, like chat rooms or message boards, so you should exercise discretion when using these services.

This privacy policy does not apply to any information you may disclose publicly in such services. You are responsible for maintaining and updating the registration information in your User Account with current and complete information.

  * [You can send an e-mail to request deactivation of your User Account.](https://secure.shell.com/home/forms/usa/aboutshell/contact_feedback/form_us_feedback.html)

###  Promotions, Credit Cards and Purchases 

To participate in some services such as sweepstakes, contests and surveys ("promotions"), to make online purchases, and to apply for a Shell credit card, you will need to provide personally identifiable information, such as name, mailing address, e-mail address, phone number, and date of birth.

Your information may be collected by Shell US or by a third party, such as a co-sponsor or a vendor involved in, or providing services in connection with, a promotion, or an e-commerce partner in the case of a credit card application or payment (e.g. Citigroup).

If you make a purchase or enter a promotion on our site, Shell US will collect your personally identifiable information, and you are deemed to consent to us providing your information to third parties who provide certain services such as processing of credit card transactions, customer service, promotions, order fulfillment and/or prize delivery, as applicable.

(As more fully described below in Use, Disclosure, and Sharing of Information - Personally Identifiable Information, these third parties are prohibited from using this information for their own marketing purposes and/or from sharing, selling, or otherwise distributing any personal data of our customers, unless you choose to opt in for such additional uses and/or disclosure by the third parties, under their respective privacy policies.)

###  Customer Service 

Some services may offer support and technical assistance through customer service centers via telephone, online chat, or e-mail. Whenever you communicate with customer service, you do so with the understanding that an operator may view and make changes to the information in your User Account in order to provide the assistance that you need.

###  Non-Personally Identifiable Information That We Collect 

Shell US automatically collects certain non-personally identifiable information about your use of the site, including the type of Internet browser or computer operating system you are using, the domain name of your Internet service provider, your "click path" through the site or "click-through" from an e-mail, the Web site or advertisement that was linked to or from this site when you visited, and your IP address.

To do this, Shell US may use cookies and other technology (see below). If you are using a wireless service, we may also automatically collect information such as the type of wireless device you are using, your mobile identification number (assigned by your telecommunications carrier) and telecommunications carrier.

Your use of our site and services, and information provided through these technologies, will be anonymous unless you provide us with personally identifiable information or have provided such information in the past.

###  Cookies and Related Technology 

This site and some services and advertisements may contain "cookies," clear gifs (also known as web beacons or web bugs), or similar technology. A cookie is a piece of data that is sent to your Internet browser, which will store the cookie on your computer if your browser is enabled to accept cookies.

Web beacons assist in the delivery of cookies and the collection of non-personally identifiable information, such as "click path" and other data as described above.

Shell US uses cookies, clear gifs, frames, server log analysis and other technologies as they are developed to customize your experience with our site and services.

Most Internet browsers will allow you to erase cookies from your computer hard drive, block acceptance of cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is stored.

You should refer to your browser instructions or "Help" screen to learn more about how to manage cookies. Please note, however, that if you block cookies, some portions of the site and services may not function properly.

We do not control cookies in third party ads, and visitors are encouraged to check the privacy policies of advertisers and/or ad services to learn about their use of cookies and other technology. The ads appearing on our site may be delivered to you by third-party advertising companies.

This Privacy Policy does not cover the use of information collected from you by third party ad servers. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, e-mail address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements on this site and other sites about goods and services that may be of interest to you.

###  Special Notice - if you are under 13 years old 

If you are under 13 years old please do not send us your personal information (for example, your name, address and email address). If you are under 13 years old and you wish to ask a question or use this site in anyway which requires you to submit your personal information please get your parent or guardian to do so on your behalf.

###  Use, Disclosure, and Sharing of Information 

###  Non-Personally Identifiable Information 

From time to time, Shell US may use and share with third parties aggregate, non-personally identifiable user information to show general demographic and preference information among users of this site.

###  Personally Identifiable Information 

Shell US uses information about you to deliver the services that you request, to keep you informed about changes affecting our services or your account, to inform you of other services or promotions in which you might be interested, and to improve and enhance our site and services.

If you opt in to receive e-mail from us, you can always opt out of future marketing messages by following the directions in each message to "unsubscribe" or by [sending an email to the Shell US site](https://secure.shell.com/home/forms/usa/aboutshell/contact_feedback/form_us_feedback.html "sending an email to the Shell US site"), or by sending postal mail to this address: [Shell Oil Company, 910 Louisiana, Ste. 4442B, Houston, TX 77002].

However, if you choose to opt out of marketing messages, we reserve the right to contact you regarding your account status, technical support, product information, changes to account terms, and any other matter that might affect our service to you and/or any products you purchased from us or registered with us, as applicable.

As stated above in Personally Identifiable Information That We Collect -  Promotions and Purchases, Shell US may also work with third parties to provide some services on our sites.

In connection with those services, you are deemed to consent to us sharing your information with third parties who provide services such as issuing Shell US credit cards, processing credit card transactions, customer service, promotion administration, order fulfillment and/or prize delivery, as applicable.

Third parties who provide, or participate in, services on this site are prohibited from using our customers' personally identifiable information for marketing purposes and/or from sharing, selling, or otherwise using such information, unless you choose to opt in to marketing, sharing, or other uses by the third parties.

If you do not want your information to be used for marketing (or other purposes unrelated to the provision of services you have requested) by a third party who participates in a service on one of our sites, do not opt in to such use by that third party when you register to participate in the service.

Please note that whenever you opt in to receive future communications from a third party, your information will be subject to the third party's privacy policy.

If you later decide that you do not want that third party to use your information, you will need to contact the third party directly, as we have no control over how third parties use information. You should always review the privacy policy of any party that collects your information to determine how that entity will handle your information.

Where we disclose your personal data for purposes which are different to those described above we will obtain your consent prior to disclosure.

Except as set out in this privacy policy, Shell US will not disclose any personally identifiable information without express permission unless legally entitled or required to do so (by legal process or for the purposes of prevention of fraud or other crime or to comply with applicable laws) or in the event of a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or substantially all of Shell US’ assets.

###  Keeping our records accurate 

We aim to keep our information about you as accurate as possible.

  * [If you would like to review or change the details you have supplied us with, please send an email.](https://secure.shell.com/home/forms/usa/aboutshell/contact_feedback/form_us_feedback.html)

###  Security of your personal data 

We have implemented technology and policies with the objective of protecting your personal information from unauthorised access and improper use and will update these measures as new technology becomes available, as appropriate.

###  Use of your personal information submitted to other web sites 

We cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of other web sites even if:

  * you accessed the third party web site using links from this site; or you linked to this site from a third party web site. 
  * We recommend that you check the policy of each site you visit and contact the owner or operator of such web site if you have any concerns or questions. 

###  Data transfers 

Personal information collected on this site may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which Shell or its affiliates, subsidiaries or agents maintain facilities, and by using this site, you consent to any such transfer of information outside of the United States.

By way of example, this may happen if any of our servers are located in a country outside of the US or one of our service providers is located in a country outside of the US. These countries may not have similar data protection laws to the US.

If we transfer your information outside of the US in this way, we will take steps to ensure that your privacy rights continue to be protected. In addition, if you use our services while you are outside the US, your information may be transferred outside the US in order to provide you with those services.

###  Will this privacy policy change? 

From time to time we may make changes to this privacy policy to reflect changes in our services and customer feedback. When we post changes to this policy, we will revise the "last updated" date at the bottom of the policy.

If there are material changes to this policy or in how we will use your personal information, we will notify you either by prominently posting a notice of such changes prior to implementing the change, by directly sending you a notification. We encourage you to periodically review this policy.

###  How you can contact us 

  * [If you would like to contact Shell.com about our privacy policy, you can do so by emailing the US Webmaster.](https://secure.shell.com/home/forms/usa/aboutshell/contact_feedback/form_us_feedback.html)
